Guide to the Elizabeth L. Eisenstein Papers, 1936-2015
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Elizabeth L. Eisenstein Papers
1936-2015
Eisenstein, Elizabeth L., 1923-2016
29 cubic feet (81 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Includes correspondence, manuscripts and typescripts, research and writing notes, contracts and financial statements, academic administrative papers, syllabi and teaching notes, programs and other conference materials; subject files; and scholarly papers by professional colleagues. Files also hold a wide variety of printed materials related to Eisenstein's scholarly interests. The collection also includes datebooks and a small amount of realia.
Biographical Note
Elizabeth Lewisohn Eisenstein (1923-2016) was a scholar of early-modern France and the history of printing. Born in New York City, she attended the Lincoln School and Vassar College, from which she graduated in the Class of 1945-44. She earned her Ph.D. in history from Radcliffe College in 1953. From 1959 to 1974 she taught as an adjunct professor at American University in Washington, D. C., where she lived for most her life. In 1974 she joined the faculty of the University of Michigan, serving there as the Alice Freeman Palmer Professor of History until her retirement in 1988. In 1979 she was named a resident consultant to the Center for the Book at the Library of Congress. She also served on the board of governors of the Folger Shakespeare Library and taught in its Folger Institute seminar series. A dedicated and influential scholar, Eisenstein produced numerous monographs, articles, lectures, and book reviews. Her most famous work was The Printing Press as an Agent of Change (1979), a two-volume study that established her as one of the foremost historians of printing in the world. She received several awards and honors for her work, including the 2002 Award for Scholarly Distinction from the American Historical Association and fellowships from the Guggenheim and Rockefeller foundations and the National Endowment for the Humanities. As well as a renowned scholar, Eisenstein was a skilled tennis player who competed internationally in senior tournaments.
Scope and Content Note
The Elizabeth L. Eisenstein Papers documents the life and career of historian Elizabeth Lewisohn Eisenstein. The materials in the collection encompasses personal and professional correspondence, the latter including letters to and from prominent scholars of the early modern period and book history; manuscripts and typescripts of her writings; research and writing notes; contracts and financial statements pertaining to publication; academic administrative papers; syllabi and teaching notes; programs and other conference materials; subject files; scholarly papers by professional colleagues; maps and other travel materials; and a variety of printed material related to her scholarly interests. The collection also includes date books and a small amount of realia. Of particular interest are the correspondence and other materials relating to Eisenstein's debate with the scholar Adrian Johns over Eisenstein's interpretation of the impact of print technology on Western culture.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Related Material
The Elizabeth L. Eisenstein Collection on the History of Books and Printing
Subject Headings
Names:
Darnton, Robert; Davis, Natalie Zemon, 1928-; Hunt, Lynn, 1945-; Johns, Adrian
Organizations:
American University (Washington, D.C.). Department of History; Folger Shakespeare Library; Library of Congress. Center for the Book; University of Michigan. Department of History
Subjects:
Book industries and trade--France--History; France--History--Revolution, 1789-1799; Intellectual life; Journalism--France--History; Printing--History--Europe; Publishers and publishing--France--History
Document Types:
Appointment books; Manuscripts (documents); Typescripts
VCL Categories:
History and Historians
Encoding Information
Encoded by Mark Seidl, May-June 2016. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, March 2024.
Acquisition Information
Bequest of the Eisenstein Family, 2017.
Series List
- Series I. Correspondence, 1958-2015
  This series consists of the bulk of Eisenstein's personal and professional correspondence. Of particular interest is the correspondence with and/or pertaining to prominent scholars such as Robert Darnton, Natalie Zemon Davis, and Lynn Hunt, and Adrian Johns. The series is arranged alphabetically by principal correspondent.
- Series II. Writings, circa 1938-2015
  This series encompasses Eisenstein's writings from her early high school and undergraduate essays to the autobiographical project she undertook late in life. The series is divided into six subseries: Student Papers, Books, Articles, Book Reviews, Lecture, and Memoir. The first, Student Papers, is arranged chronologically. The remaining subseries are arranged alphabetically by title of the work. The materials include manuscript notes, typescripts (many with Eisenstein's annotations), offprints, and reviews of Eisenstein's books. Many files also contain correspondence pertaining to the work.
- Series III. Conference Materials, 1963-2013
  This series consists of materials pertaining to the many conferences Eisenstein attended. The materials included programs, announcements, copies of papers Eisenstein presented or on which she commented, and some correspondence. Arranged alphabetically by title of conference.
- Series IV. Publishing Files, 1980-2013
  Materials in this series include publisher contracts, royalty statements, and some correspondence with publishers. Arranged alphabetically by publisher.
- Series V. Professional Files, 1952 - circa 2015
  This series consists of materials pertaining to Eisenstein's positions in the history departments of American University and the University of Michigan. The materials include departmental memos, meeting agendas, annual reports, and some correspondence with colleagues, department chairs, and other institutional officials. Arranged alphabetically by institution.
- Series VI. Awards and Honors, 1981-2013
  This series consists of awards Eisenstein received for her scholarship, honorary degrees, and others honors. Some files contain correspondence pertaining to the award. Arranged alphabetically by name of award/honor.
- Series VII. Teaching Materials, 1967-2012
  Materials in this series include syllabi, reading lists, and class notes. Some files contain correspondence pertaining to particular courses. Arranged alphabetically by institution.
- Series VIII. Organization/Society Materials, 1965-2008
  This series consists of materials relating to Eisenstein's service with several professional organizations and societies. The materials include memos, meeting agendas, brochures and announcements, and some correspondence pertaining to the business of the organization. Arranged alphabetically by name of organization.
- Series IX. Colleagues' Papers, 1936-2013
  Materials in this series include typescripts of papers sent to Eisenstein for comment (many with her marginal annotations), offprints of articles with authors' inscriptions to Eisenstein, and some correspondence pertaining to the papers. Arranged alphabetically by author of the paper(s).
- Series X. Travel Materials, 1967-2014
  Materials in this series include maps, itineraries, travel documents, tourism literature, and some correspondence pertaining to travel arrangements and related matters. Arranged alphabetically by destination.
- Series XI. Subject Files, 1958-2015
  The files in this series contain materials brought together by Eisenstein and have been retained in their original order. The materials include mainly photocopies and offprints of articles, correspondence, and clippings and other printed materials related to topics of scholarly and personal interest. Arranged alphabetically.
- Series XII. Printed Materials, 1968-2016
  This series consists of photocopies of scholarly articles, newsletters and bulletins, book catalogues, exhibition brochures, magazine and newspaper clippings, and other printed matter. Arranged alphabetically.
- Series XIII. Miscellaneous Materials, 1962-2015
  These materials include hand-written bibliographical references and notes, datebooks, and realia.
- Series XIV. Professional Evaluations (restricted), undated
  This series includes the recommendations, teaching and tenure reviews, and other professional evaluations Eisenstein wrote throughout her career. These materials are closed to research due to personal privacy issues.
Container List
- SERIES I. CORRESPONDENCE
  - Adams, Thomas R./Rudolf Hirsch, 1967-1974 (Folder 69.1)
  - Ali, Tariq, 2002 (Folder 1.1)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1985 (Folder 1.2)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1993-1994 (Folder 1.3)
  - American Historical Association, 1994 (Folder 1.4)
  - American Historical Review, 1969 (Folder 1.5)
  - American Historical Review, circa 1971-1972 (Folder 1.6)
  - American Historical Review, 1979 (Folder 1.7)
  - American Scholar, 1995 (Folder 1.8)
  - American Society for Eighteenth-Century Studies, 1970 (Folder 1.9)
  - American Society for Eighteenth-Century Studies, 1995 (Folder 1.10)
  - Ancien Regime Group, 2014 (Folder 1.11)
  - American University, 2013-2015 (Folder 1.12)
  - Arion Press, 1981 (Folder 1.13)
  - Australian Research Council, 1996 (Folder 1.14)
  - Aydelott, Judy, 2014 (Folder 1.15)
  - Bognall, Roger S., 1990 (Folder 1.16)
  - Baker, Keith, 1985-1986 (Folder 1.17)
  - Ballester, Mencia Caro, 2015 (Folder 1.18)
  - Barber, Bernard, 1993 (Folder 1.19)
  - Barker, W. W., 1981 (Folder 1.20)
  - Barkun, Michael, 1976 (Folder 1.21)
  - BBC Radio, 1996 (Folder 1.22)
  - Belanger, Terry, 1985-1992 (Folder 1.23)
  - Bell, Bill, 1994 (Folder 1.24)
  - Bell, David A., 2001-2009 (Folder 1.25)
  - Bell, David A./Donald Sutherland, 2004 (Folder 1.26)
  - Ben [?], 1978 (Folder 1.27)
  - Berkvens-Stevenlinck, Christiane/Librairie Droz, 1988-1991 (Folder 1.28)
  - Billington, James, 187-1988 (Folder 1.29)
  - Billington, James/Charles Blitzer, 1989 (Folder 1.30)
  - Birn, Raymond/Natalie Z. Davis/M. A. Edelstein/Smith Fussnor/ D. E. Gerard/Howard J. Graham/Frank Kaffler/Robert M. Kingdon, 1965-1972 (Folder 1.31)
  - Bogels, Theo, 1965-1972 (Folder 1.32)
  - Bolter, J. David, 1983 (Folder 1.33)
  - Brock, W. H., 1983 (Folder 1.34)
  - Brown, Kenneth, 1999 (Folder 1.35)
  - Burgess Publishing Company/Robert M. Kingdon, 1971-1974 (Folder 1.36)
  - Burke, Peter, 1983 (etc.) (Folder 1.37)
  - Cambridge University Press, 1970-1974 (Folder 1.38)
  - Cambridge University Press, 1977-1978 (Folder 69.2)
  - Cambridge University Press, 1984-1985 (Folder 1.39)
  - Cambridge University Press, 1989 (Folder 1.40)
  - Cambridge University Press, 1992 (Folder 1.41)
  - Cambridge University Press - translations, 1984-1996 (Folder 1.42)
  - Cambridge University Press - translations, 1995-2015 (Folder 1.43)
  - Cambridge University Press/Editions du Seuil, 1978-1980 (Folder 69.3)
  - Carey, James W., 1982 (Folder 2.1)
  - Cazes, Helene, 2005 (Folder 2.2)
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1989-1991 (Folder 2.3)
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 2015 (Folder 2.4)
  - Center for Renaissance and Baroque Studies, 1989 (Folder 2.5)
  - Centre Georges Pompidou, 2987 (Folder 69.4)
  - Challinor, Joan, 2007 (Folder 2.6)
  - Chartier, Roger, 1981-1982 (Folder 2.7)
  - Chicago Library System, 1998-1999 (Folder 2.8)
  - Chizuka, Tadami, 1989 (Folder 2.9)
  - Chronicle of Higher Education, 2010 (Folder 2.10)
  - Clausen, Carol, 2007 (Folder 2.11)
  - Coe, Richard M., 1958 (Folder 69.5)
  - Coldiron, Anne, 2002 (Folder 2.12)
  - Cole, John Y., 2007 (Folder 2.13)
  - Collinge, Maura Elford/Bill Sherman, 2011 (Folder 2.14)
  - Columbia University, 1985-1986 (Folder 2.15)
  - Cowan, Brian, 2006 (Folder 2.16)
  - Cresswell, Don/Arthur Williamson, 1999-2000 (Folder 2.17)
  - Cressy, David, 2003 (Folder 2.18)
  - Crowley, David, 2005-2009 (Folder 2.19)
  - Csiszar, Alex, 2012 (Folder 2.20)
  - Daedalus, 1982-1997 (Folder 2.21)
  - Daphne [?], 2004 (Folder 2.22)
  - Dasgupta, Rana, 1997-1998 (Folder 2.23)
  - Dashkalova, Krassimira, 1995 (Folder 2.24)
  - Declined invitations, 1967-2008 (Folder 2.25-2.27)
  - de Maria, Robert, 1988-1989 (Folder 3.1)
  - de Maria, Robert, 2008 (Folder 3.2)
  - Dennis, Everette G., 1995 (Folder 3.3)
  - Devon, Tonia K., 1993 (Folder 3.4)
  - Dirda, Michael, 2005 (Folder 3.5)
  - Doggett, Rachel, 1982 (Folder 3.6)
  - Downey, Jim/Ted Eisenstein/Lisa McGuire, 2014 (Folder 3.7)
  - Dugas, Don-John, 2001 (Folder 3.8)
  - East-Central American Society for Eighteenth-Century Studies, 1996 (Folder 3.9)
  - Eisenstein, Julian, 2002 (Folder 3.10)
  - Elena, Alberto, 1988 (Folder 69.6)
  - Ellis, Harold, 1981 (Folder 3.11)
  - Emory University, 1982 (Folder 3.12)
  - Epstein, Joseph, 1989 (Folder 3.13)
  - Foreign correspondence, 1972-2005 (Folder 69.7)
  - Francomano, Emily, 2011 (Folder 3.14)
  - Friedman, Judith, 1994 (Folder 3.15)
  - Friguglietti, James, 1986-1997 (Folder 3.16)
  - Garrett, Clarke, 1972-1978 (Folder 3.17)
  - Garrett, John, 1988 (Folder 3.18)
  - Germani, Ian, 1983 (Folder 3.19)
  - Gifford, Prosser, 1995 (Folder 3.20)
  - Global Library Project, undated (Folder 3.21)
  - Goodman, Dena, 1987-2000 (Folder 3.22)
  - Gorman, Michael John, 2001 (Folder 3.23)
  - Goudie, Andrew, 2004-2005 (Folder 3.24)
  - Granfton, Anthony, 1993-2003 (Folder 3.25)
  - Graham, Andrew, 1990 (Folder 3.26)
  - Graham, Kay/Lucy Moorhead, 1997-2004 (Folder 3.27)
  - Graubard, Stephen R., 1995 (Folder 3.28)
  - Grew, Daphne M./Comparative Studies in Society and History, 1969 (Folder 3.29)
  - Grout, Nancy, 1989 (Folder 3.30)
  - Haakonssen, Knut and Lisabeth, 1985 (Folder 3.31)
  - Harvard Magazine, 2011 (Folder 3.32)
  - Harvard University, 1980 (Folder 3.33)
  - Harvard University, Department of History, 1952-1961 (Folder 3.34)
  - Harvard University, /Harvard University Press, 1957-1968 (Folder 3.34)
  - Harvey, John L., 2009 (Folder 4.1)
  - Harvey, John L., 2014 (Folder 4.2)
  - Hauben, Machael and Ronda, 1996 (Folder 4.3)
  - Henry, D. H. W., 1996 (Folder 4.4)
  - Hewlett-Packard Laboratories Research Library, 1997 (Folder 4.5)
  - Hexter, J. H., 1994 (Folder 4.6)
  - Hindman, Sandra, 1977 (Folder 4.7)
  - Hirsch, Rudolf, 1974; [Includes summary of Eisenstein's letter to Past and Present] (Folder 4.8)
  - History and Theory, 1965-1966 (Folder 4.9)
  - Holt, Thomas C., 1982-1995 (Folder 4.10)
  - Hunt, Arnold, 2007 (Folder 4.11)
  - Jacob, Margaret, 2007 (Folder 4.12)
  - Jacobs, Greg, 1999 (Folder 4.13)
  - Janacek, Bruce, 2004 (Folder 4.14)
  - Jarvis, Jeff, 2010 (Folder 4.15)
  - Jones, Derek, 1996 (Folder 4.16)
  - Journal of Modern History, 1966-1967 (Folder 4.17)
  - Kafker, Frank/James M. Laux/Patricia M. Fox/Paul L. Ward David H. Tiffany, 1966-1969 (Folder 4.18)
  - Kakutani, Michiko, 1996 (Folder 4.19)
  - Kates, Gary, 1980-1989 (Folder 4.20)
  - Kates, Gary, 1996 (Folder 4.21)
  - King, Jamie, 2007 (Folder 4.22)
  - Kittay, Jeffrey S., 1985 (Folder 4.23)
  - Kjaergaard, Thorkild, 1983-1987 (Folder 4.24)
  - Kates, Gary, 1980-1989 (Folder 4.25)
  - Kubie, Lawrence S., 1906-1961 (Folder 4.26)
  - Kupperman, Karen/Bonnie Smith, 2013-2014 (Folder 4.27)
  - Langer, Ulirch, circa 1998 (Folder 4.28)
  - Leary, David E., 1983 (Folder 4.29)
  - Legal correspondence, 1998-2005 (Folder 4.30)
  - Lerner, Daniel, 1970 (Folder 4.31)
  - Levin, Miriam, 1994 (Folder 4.32)
  - Levy, Darlene Gay, 1992 (Folder 4.33)
  - Lewis, Ben, 1998 (Folder 4.34)
  - Library of Congress, 1976-1978 (Folder 4.35)
  - MacKenzie [?], 2004 (Folder 5.1)
  - Malatesta, Geri, 1990-1994 (Folder 5.2)
  - Manguel, Alberto, 1997-2001 (Folder 5.3)
  - Mann, Erika, 2000-2008 (Folder 5.4)
  - Martin, John, 1998 (Folder 5.5)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1978 (Folder 5.6)
  - McLeod, Michael, 2001 (Folder 5.7)
  - Mellot, Jean-Dominique, 2004 (Folder 5.8)
  - Merker, Kim, 1990-1993 (Folder 5.9)
  - Merton, Robert K., 1965-1967 (Folder 5.10)
  - Merton, Robert K., 1986-1987 (Folder 5.11)
  - Milberg, Leonard and Ellen, 2000-2001 (Folder 5.12)
  - Montagnes, Ian, 1982 (Folder 5.13)
  - Moorhead, Lucy, undated (Folder 5.14)
  - Moyal, Ann, 1990-1991 (Folder 5.15)
  - Murphy, Cullen, 2015 (Folder 5.16)
  - National Humanities Center, 1980-1981 (Folder 5.17)
  - New York Times Book Review, 1993 (Folder 5.18)
  - New York Times, Letters to the Editor, 1980 (Folder 5.19)
  - Nord, David Paul, 2004 (Folder 5.20)
  - O'Gorman, Frank, 1988 (Folder 5.21)
  - Ohles, Frederick F., 1982 (Folder 5.22)
  - Orr, Clarissa, circa 1973-circa 1978 (Folder 5.23)
  - Osborn, J. R., 2005-2011 (Folder 5.24)
  - Oxford University Press, 1990-2009 (Folder 5.25)
  - Oxford University Press, 1992-1993 (Folder 5.26)
  - Padgett, Matthew, 2010 (Folder 5.27)
  - Paideia, 1981-1982 (Folder 5.28)
  - Palmer, Leigh Ann, 2005 (Folder 5.29)
  - Palter, Robert, 1971-1973 (Folder 5.30)
  - Parker, Harold, 1985 (Folder 5.31)
  - Past and Present/Journal of the History of Ideas/ History and Theory, 1967-1969 (Folder 69.8)
  - Penn State University Press, 1995 (Folder 5.32)
  - Phelan, Catherine, 2006 (Folder 5.33)
  - Pierpont Morgan Library, 1993 (Folder 5.34)
  - Popkin, Sam, 2003 (Folder 5.35)
  - Portand State University, 1981 (Folder 5.36)
  - Postman, Neil, 1985 (Folder 5.37)
  - Priest, W. Curtiss/Mary Alice White/Society for the History of Technology, 1987-1988 (Folder 6.1)
  - Printing History, 1980 (Folder 6.2)
  - Publishers' correspondence, circa 1965-circa 1977 (Folder 69.9)
  - Rainie, Lee, 2005-2007 (Folder 6.3)
  - Reed, Walter, 1982 (Folder 6.4)
  - Reichl, [?], 2013 (Folder 6.5)
  - Reinharz, Jehuda, undated (Folder 6.6)
  - Renaissance and Reformation-Renaissance et Reforme, 1978 (Folder 6.7)
  - Renaissance Society of America, 1972 (Folder 6.8)
  - Renaissance Society of America, 1994-1995 (Folder 6.9)
  - Revel, Jacques, 1983-1985 (Folder 6.10)
  - Richter, Michael, 1975 (Folder 6.11)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1976 (Folder 6.12)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1976-1977 (Folder 6.13)
  - Rosen, Edward, 1974 (Folder 6.14)
  - Rouse, Ricahrd/Mary Martin McLaughlin, 1971-1973 (Folder 6.15)
  - Sally [?], 1988 (Folder 6.16)
  - Salmon, John, 1981 (Folder 6.17)
  - Schanne, Michael, 1992 (Folder 6.18)
  - Schneider, Robert A./David D. Bien, 1997 (Folder 6.19)
  - Schonfeld, Roger, 2006 (Folder 6.20)
  - Schutte, Anne/John Ahern/Jane Walpole/Robert Kingdon, 1979 (Folder 6.21)
  - Schwartz, Hillel, 1991 (Folder 6.22)
  - The Scriptorium Center for Christian Antiquities, 1996 (Folder 6.23)
  - Segre, Dan/Yehuda Elkana/Rivka Ra'am, 1984-1985 (Folder 6.24)
  - Seligman, Ned, 2010 (Folder 6.25)
  - Sheehan, J., 1988 (Folder 6.26)
  - Sher, Richard, 1995-2006 (Folder 6.27)
  - Sheridan, Mary Anne, 2013 (Folder 6.28)
  - Shevlin, Eleanor/Richerd Sher, 2002 (Folder 6.29)
  - Shevlin, Eleanor, 2010-2011 (Folder 6.30)
  - Skib, Bryan A., 2005 (Folder 6.31)
  - Shoults, Rhiannon C., 2008 (Folder 6.32)
  - Slavin, Arthur J., circa 1974-circa 2004 (Folder 6.33)
  - Slavin, Morris, 1998 (Folder 6.34)
  - Smith Frank (Cambridge University Press), 1983-1984 (Folder 69.10)
  - Smith Frank (Cambridge University Press), 2007-2009 (Folder 6.35)
  - Society for the History of Authorship, Reading, and Publishing, 1994 (Folder 6.36)
  - Society for the History of Technology, 1986 (Folder 6.37)
  - Solomon, Howard M./Guggenheim Foundation/Rockefeller Foundation, 1973-1979 (Folder 6.38)
  - Sovern, Michael I., 1980 (Folder 6.39)
  - Sponberg, Michael R., 1975 (Folder 6.40)
  - St. Clair, William/Peter Stallybrass, 2005 (Folder 6.41)
  - Stallybrass, Peter, 2000-2001 (Folder 6.42)
  - Stephens, Mitchell, 1995-1996 (Folder 6.43)
  - Stone, Bailey, 1987 (Folder 6.44)
  - Strauss, Gerald, circa 1980 (Folder 6.45)
  - Sutherland, D. M. G., 1988-1994 (Folder 6.46)
  - Teichgraber, Richard, 1986 (Folder 6.47)
  - Tetel, Marcel, 1979 (Folder 6.48)
  - Trescott, Martha M., 1975 (Folder 6.49)
  - University of Glasgow, 1983-1984 (Folder 6.50)
  - University of Michigan, 1979-1987 (Folder 6.51)
  - University of Michigan, 2000 (Folder 6.52)
  - University of Michigan/Folger Shakespeare Library, 1972-1974 (Folder 6.53)
  - University of Oregon. Department of History, 1979 (Folder 7.1)
  - University of Oxford, 1989-1990 (Folder 69.11)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 2009-2010 (Folder 7.2)
  - University of Pennsylvania Press, 2010 (Folder 7.3)
  - University of Texas at Austin, 1981-1982 (Folder 7.4)
  - University of Washington. Department of History, 1983-1985 (Folder 7.5)
  - Van Kley, Dalek/Kieth Baker, 1985-1986 (Folder 7.6)
  - Vassar College, 1998 (Folder 7.7)
  - Vassar College, 2000-2007 (Folder 7.8)
  - Vassar College. Department of History, 1978 (Folder 69.12)
  - Vassar College. Office of Development, 2001 (Folder 7.9)
  - Wagner, Peter, 1990 (Folder 7.10)
  - Waldron, T. P., 1981 (Folder 7.11)
  - Walsh, Marcus, 2003 (Folder 7.12)
  - Walton, Kendall, 1990-1994 (Folder 7.13)
  - Washington Edpress, 1996 (Folder 7.14)
  - Wasserstrom, Jeff, 2001 (Folder 7.15)
  - Weiner, Dora B., 2004 (Folder 7.16)
  - Wellish, Hans H., 1986 (Folder 7.17)
  - Werking, Richard, 2005 (Folder 7.18)
  - Wilson, Guy/Charles G. Nauert, Jr., 1991-1992 (Folder 7.19)
  - Wolfson College, Oxford, 1989-1990 (Folder 7.20)
  - Wolfson College, Oxford, 1995 (Folder 7.21)
  - Wood, Anne ["Sis"], 2011 (Folder 7.22)
  - Wood, Anne ["Sis"], 2014 (Folder 7.23)
  - Wray, Shannon, 2001 (Folder 7.24)
  - Yale University Press, 2004 (Folder 7.25)
  - Yardeni, Myriam, 1989-1990 (Folder 7.26)
  - Zard, Abby, 2006 (Folder 7.27)
  - Ziegler, Georgianna, 2013 (Folder 7.28)
  - Zitch, Robert P., III, 2014 (Folder 7.29)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1966-2013 (Folders 7.30-34)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1966-2013 (Folders 8.1-17)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1966-2013 (Folders 69.13-14)
  - Unidentified correspondence, 1986 (Folder 8.18)
- SERIES II. WRITINGS
  - Student Papers
    - Lincoln School, circa 1938-1941 (Folder 9.1)
    - Vassar College, 1941-1944 (Folders 9.2-4)
    - Radcliffe College, 1946 (Folders 9.5-7)
    - Radcliffe College, 1952; [dissertation] (Folders 9.8, 10.1-8, 11.1-2)
  - Articles
    - The Advents of Printing and the Problem of the Renaissance, 1970; [correspondence pertaining to] (Folder 11.3)
    - The Advents of Printing and the Problem of the Renaissance: A Reply, 1971 (Folder 11.4)
    - Buonarroti, Filippo Michele, 1964 (Folder 69.15)
    - Buonarroti, Filippo Michele, 1980 (Folder 11.5)
    - Bypassing the Enlightenment, 1997 (Folder 69.16)
    - Class in the French Revolution: a Discussion, 1967 (Folder 11.6)
    - Clio and Chronos, 1966 (Folder 11.7)
    - Clio and Chronos, circa 1966 (Folders 70.1-3)
    - Divine Art/Infernal Machine, 1996 (Folder 11.8)
    - The Early Printer as "Renaissance Man,", 1981 (Folder 11.9)
    - The Emergence of Print Culture in the West, circa 1980 (Folder 11.10)
    - The End of the Book?, 1994-1995, circa 1995 (Folders 11.11-12)
    - Enlightenment Thought and Print Culture, circa 1985 (Folder 70.4)
    - The Fifteenth Century Book Revolution, circa 1980 (Folder 11.13)
    - The Fifteenth Century Media Revolution, 1993 (Folder 11.14)
    - From the Printed Word to the Moving Image, 1978 (Folder 11.15)
    - From the Printed Word to the Moving Image, 1997 (Folder 12.1)
    - Gods, Devils, and Gutenberg, 1998 (Folder 12.2)
    - The Gutenberg Galaxy: and Historian's View, 1981-1991, circa 1984 (Folders 12.3-4)
    - How revolutionary was the Print Revolution?, 2002 (Folder 12.5)
    - The Introduction of Graphic Printing, 1980-1983 (Folder 12.6)
    - The Introduction of Graphic Printing, 1983-1994 (Folder 12.7)